goodlifehealthclubs.com.au 2019-03-15

# Privacy Policy - Goodlife Health Clubs

## FIND OUT MORE ABOUT THE GOODLIFE PRIVACY POLICY

### 1\. OVERVIEW

Goodlife Operations Pty Ltd and Hypoxi Australia Pty Ltd (together “Goodlife”, “we” or “us”) own and operate the following Australian-based businesses:  
Goodlife Health Clubs HYPOXI Australia Goodlife is committed to protecting the privacy of its customers’ personal information in accordance with the Privacy Act 1988 and the Australian Privacy Principles. This Privacy Policy sets out the standard of protection you can expect.

Our Privacy Policy explains how we handle your personal information (including any sensitive information, such as health information). In particular it details how we collect, use, disclose, store and enable you to access your personal information. This Privacy Policy applies only to Goodlife Health Clubs Australian businesses.

### 2\. CONSENT

Our Privacy Policy applies to your personal information regardless of the way in which we collect it, for example, whether it is collected via one of our websites, when you visit one of our venues, when you contact one of our customer service departments or visit one of our social media sites. By submitting information to us and/or accessing and using our websites or social media platforms you consent to us using and disclosing your personal information in the ways described in this Privacy Policy.

### 3\. YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION

Personal information includes any information or opinion about an identified individual, or an individual who is reasonably identifiable regardless of whether the information is true or not. Goodlife only collects personal information (and sensitive health information) which is necessary for, or related to, one or more of its functions or activities. The types of personal information we collect from you will depend upon the type of interaction that you have with us. Broadly speaking, the types of personal information that we collect may include:

  * your name, address, email address and telephone details;
  * age and date of birth;
  * credit card, bank account details and tax file numbers;
  * health information – if you intend to use one of our venues or services where your health status may be a consideration;
  * whether you are a member of one of our commercial partners with whom we organise discounts or other promotional arrangements for members and customers;
  * where applicable your licence, vehicle registration and insurance details;
  * your image, if you are photographed at one of our venues; and
  * if you apply for a job in one of our businesses, details about your education, employment history, membership of professional associations, referees and next of kin.

Where we collect sensitive information from you (such as health information or details of memberships of professional associations) we will only do so with your consent. 

### 4\. HOW WE COLLECT YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION

We may collect personal information from you in a number of ways, including:

  * when you send us an e-mail, “contact us” message or make any other form of written enquiry;
  * via mobile sites, applications, widgets and other mobile interactive features (collectively “Apps”), for example, when you provide feedback via a QR Code App;
  * via our official social media pages that we control, such as the official pages for our various businesses on Facebook, Twitter and Instagram;
  * when you visit or call one of our venues to ask about our services;
  * when you sign up to use our services, whether online or in person;
  * when you make a booking at one of our venues;
  * when you enter a promotion, competition, provide feedback or participate in a survey, market research or other promotional activities which we (or one of our agents) conduct;
  * when you sign up to receive our newsletters or marketing material;
  * if your photograph is taken at one of our venues; and
  * when you submit an application for employment with us.

Some of our venues have surveillance cameras which may capture your image on film. We may use this information in respect of the management and security of our venues and it may be provided to law enforcement and government bodies for these purposes. We may also collect personal information from third parties, for example:

  * your friends via a refer a friend promotion;
  * our commercial partners with whom we organise discounts or other promotional arrangements for members and customers;
  * someone duly authorised to act on your behalf;
  * debit and payment service providers who process transactions on behalf of our various businesses;
  * market research organisations we engage to conduct market research;
  * our official pages on social media platforms and from people with whom you are friends or otherwise connected on social media platforms; and
  * recruiters we have retained and from referees you have provided in support of a job application.

### 5\. ACCESS BY CHILDREN

As we cannot distinguish the age of people accessing our websites, our Privacy Policy applies to all individuals. If a person under sixteen years of age has provided us with personal information without parental or guardian consent, those details may be removed by emailing us at [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection)

### 6\. HOW WE USE YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION

Your personal information may be used by us in a number of ways, including: 

  * for the purpose requested;
  * to respond to your query or feedback;
  * to process your application for membership of one of our businesses or to use or purchase one of our products or services;
  * to process your order;
  * to promote and market all current and future Goodlife businesses, venues, products and services and to inform you about the products and services of our commercial partners;
  * to process and consider your application for employment;
  * to assist with our internal business processes;
  * for market research purposes and to improve our product and service offering;
  * to administer contests, promotions and surveys;
  * for any other purposes that you would reasonably expect; and
  * to enable us to comply with our obligations under the law.

### 7\. WHEN WE DISCLOSE YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION

We may disclose your personal information in a variety of circumstances including to:

  * related entities of Goodlife;
  * contractors, agents and suppliers we engage to provide products and/or perform services for us,
  * for example customer feedback analysts, digital marketing agencies, online shopping cart service providers, photo processing companies, payment processors and personal trainers;
  * commercial partners with whom we have agreed information sharing arrangements;
  * our professional advisors, such as lawyers and accountants;
  * law enforcement bodies;
  * a purchaser of all or part of Goodlife’s business; and
  * any other person for any other purposes that would be reasonably expected (including if required by law).

When third parties perform services on our behalf, we take reasonable steps to ensure the third party will protect your personal information in accordance with Australian privacy laws and in a manner consistent with this Privacy Policy. Third parties are required to restrict their use of the personal information to the purpose for which it was provided. We have service providers in the United States of America and New Zealand, but the location of our service providers may change from time to time. We do not sell your name or other personal information to third parties.

### 8\. ANONYMITY AND PSEUDONYMS

From time to time, you may be able to visit our venues or websites and deal with us anonymously or by pseudonym. However, we require certain personal information to be able to provide you with the services, products or information you seek. If you do not provide us with certain required information, we may not be able to provide you with access to those services or products or respond to your request or communication.

For example, we may not be able to respond to your enquiry, assess your application, enter you in a promotion, or send you requested information.

### 9\. UPDATING PERSONAL INFORMATION

We take reasonable steps to ensure that the personal information we collect and use is accurate, complete and up-to-date. However, the accuracy of the information we hold depends to a large extent on the information you provide. You can update (or request us to update) your personal information at any time. We ask you to keep your information as current as possible so that we may continue to provide you with useful information.

To update your details, please email us at [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection) Alternatively, if you have an online account with one of our businesses, you may update your details via your online account. If you would like to unsubscribe or “opt out” from receiving any direct marketing material from Goodlife, that option will be available in the relevant communication sent to you. We will respond to your unsubscribe request within a reasonable period after your request is made.

### 10\. HOW YOU CAN ACCESS, UPDATE OR REMOVE YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION

You have a right to request access to your personal information held by us. You are also able to update your details or request us to remove your details should you wish to “opt out” in the future. Should you wish to access, update or remove your details, please email us at [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection)

Alternatively, if you have an online account with one of our businesses, you may be able to access the personal information we hold about you via your online account.  
If there is a lawful reason for not providing you with access, we will provide you with a written explanation and will inform you of the mechanism to complain about our refusal at that time. Please note that we will respond to your requests as soon as reasonably practicable and we may charge a reasonable fee for doing so.

### 11\. SECURITY MEASURES TO PROTECT YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION

Goodlife takes reasonable steps to maintain the security of your personal information and to prevent the misuse, interference, loss, modification and unauthorised access to or disclosure of your personal information. 

We have implemented a variety of electronic and physical security measures to safeguard the privacy of your personal information. These measures include: 

  * your information is stored on secured networks consistent with industry standards, and is only accessible by those employees and agents who have special access rights to such systems;
  * our websites use a secure server so that credit card details provided when purchasing tickets or paying for memberships, for example, are transmitted via Secure Socket Layer (SSL) technology;
  * industry-standard encryption technologies are used when transferring or receiving sensitive information supplied by users;
  * where your information is in hardcopy form, such documents are stored in secured areas only accessible by those employees and agents with special access rights;
  * our Eftpos terminals for credit card transactions at the retail outlets are PCI Compliant to provide necessary security over credit card data;
  * our IT networks undergo necessary penetration testing to continually identify and remediate potential opportunities for unauthorised data access; and
  * periodic data recon is carried out on our point of sale systems to ensure no credit card details are stored without encryption.

We also ensure where possible that our contractors, agents, commercial partners and third party service providers have the same information security measures in place. While we strive to protect your personal information, we cannot guarantee or warrant its complete security. No data transmission over the Internet can be guaranteed to be 100% secure. If you have an online account with one of our businesses, your account will be able to be accessed by anyone who knows your login details. You should keep you login details, and any other information you use to remember these details, private and secure. 

We will not be responsible for any loss or harm that you may suffer as a result of a leak of your personal information unless we have breached this Privacy Policy or the Australian privacy laws.

### 12\. COOKIES

Your websites use cookies for identification purposes and to allow certain functions on the websites to work such as the online shopping process. A cookie is a small string of information that a website transfers to your browser for identification purposes. The cookies we pass to your electronic device are anonymous and do not hold information about you and are not capable of revealing your personal identity. However, if you nevertheless prefer not to receive cookies, you can configure your Internet browser on your electronic device to reject them, or to notify you if they are being used. Rejecting cookies can, however, limit the functionality of our websites and the online shopping process.

### 13\. GOOGLE ANALYTICS

All of our websites use Google Analytics, a web analytics service provided by Google, Inc. Google Analytics uses cookies to help the website analyse how users use the website. The information generated by the cookie about your use of one of our websites (including your IP address) will be transmitted to and stored by Google on servers in the United States of America. Google will use this information for the purpose of evaluating your use of our websites, compiling reports on website activity for website operators and providing other services relating to website activity and internet usage. Google may also transfer this information to third parties where required to do so by law, or where such third parties process the information on Google’s behalf. Google will not associate your IP address with any other data held by Google. By using our websites, you consent to the processing of data about you by Google in the manner and for the purposes set out above. You can view Google’s privacy policy by visiting their website at www.google.com.

### 14\. LINKED SITES

Our websites may contain links to other Internet websites. These links are provided solely for your convenience. If you submit personal information to or via any linked site, the privacy policy applying to that information will be outside our control. You should therefore check the privacy policy of the linked site before submitting information to or via that site.

### 15\. CHANGES TO OUR PRIVACY POLICY

From time to time we may need to change this Privacy Policy to reflect our changing business practices and/or changes in the law. We may therefore change this Privacy Policy at any time by posting the amended Privacy Policy on our websites or other social media platforms. All personal information collected and held by us will be governed by our most recent Privacy Policy as posted on our websites or other social media platforms.

### 16\. PRIVACY COMPLAINT OR CONCERN

If you have a complaint or concern about the way in which your privacy has been handled by Goodlife, please email us at [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection) We will respond by email within 2 working days confirming receipt of your complaint or concern. We will then proactively investigate your complaint or concern and provide you with our response within a reasonable timeframe. If, after receiving our response, you still consider that your privacy complaint or concern has not been resolved, you may then take your complaint to the Office of the Australian Information Commissioner (www.oaic.gov.au).
